Thank you guys, welcome to another video.
I hope you enjoyed the previous video, which we have done shooting attacks.
So that's a look at our initial axis, but we have another kind of initial axis.
So here we have our VPNs, so most of the time, the ransomware that attacked us, they will
be using the VPN portal for an initial axis.
Okay, as I already said, I already said that we will be using a VPN.
If you know the username is not password, you can just login to the organization directly
without any, there will be no, there will be different mechanism will work in that situation,
okay.
It will be like a normal login, normal user login.
So let me show you something and somewhere, let's, VPN.
So you can see often expired vulnerabilities in the VPN portal, okay.
So the ransomware that attacked us, the hackers, the most of the time, they will be targeting
their VPNs.
In my experience, we are facing like 65 to 70% of the attacks from the VPN portal, okay.
So because they can easily use the VPN vulnerabilities and they can easily get into the
mission.
It will be a very easy kind of attack, okay.
So here you can see a new queue in ransomware attack, users of VPN currency also, okay.
So it uses a VPN currency also and there will be a lot, a lot, a lot of ransomware.
So let me pull here.
So here you can see, I hear our ransomware gang targeting phonic wall VPNs.
And there will be a many ransomware, but let me give you a lot of bit.
So here we can find the Akira log with they are targeting the Cisco VPNs and the threat
actors will be easily targeting the VPNs and they get into the environment, okay.
So the finding the VPN stuffs are easy.
So we know the forte gates are providing the VPN.
So if you search for a forte gate, in showdown, this is a showdown.
So maybe you know about the showdown.
So it will be like a network scanners, so we can scan, it's an online scanner.
So we can scan what are the ports and what are the services are running inside the organization,
okay.
So here you can find there is a 45,000, 48,000, 48,000, 181 results are there.
So there is four lakhs plus customers are using the forte gate VPN.
Maybe many of the customers will be vulnerable to any of the VPN based attack, VPN based
attack.
So you can find the recent cvs here, 48, CVE, 2024.
So there will be a lot of lot of cv, so you can see the open, a specific version attack.
So we face to this kind of attack also, regers in attack one time, okay.
There will be a many cvs will be there.
And then here there will be a six seven cvs will be published for our VPNs and protect us
we're literally using the VPNs and they will be doing initial access.
So here you can find there is a remote code execution vulnerability, so another to get
attack us can able to, if they are not authenticated also, if they do not know the username
and password also, they can execute the remote code inside the VPNs, okay.
They can literally, they can execute the remote code in the portal, okay.
So from this URL like that, okay.
So this will be one of the easy victim for the attack to us will be targeting the organization,
okay.
So you need to take care about that.
This kind of questions will be asked in an interview behavior based questions like how
the attack this will be compromising the environment.
So if you have an idea about they will be using the VPNs or they will be using a phishing
or some other vulnerability, so you can easily crack the interface most of the time, but
this is the knowledge we score so you can increase your knowledge based on that, okay.
So anyway at the point of view, we are using our knowledge to any of the field domains
right.
So any of the work are any attending in this.
Here you can find the username and password, so you can log in to the machine.
So if you have, if you can able to brute force this, you can get into the machine.
So I hope someone, someone have some of them know how the brute force will be happened.
So no problem, we will be covering the brute force in this section only.
So let's keep that.
Yeah.
So there's a lot of VPNs, so I just did a 48 and there's a Cisco VPN also there.
So if we search for a Cisco VPN, the Sudan will be reflecting the Cisco VPN based who are
all using the Cisco based application.
So here you can find the Cisco based VPN.
So I already said it's like, it will, it will be scanning the network organization.
It's an online scanner basically, okay.
So here you can find portable, portable, open and Cisco, ESL, ASASL, VPNOS, they are, okay.
So if you know the username and password, so you can directly get into the organization
and you can easily enter into the organization, okay.
There's a Sony call also, Sony call also have a, so here you can find Cisco.
Cisco, VPN, it was asking for a username and password if you know the username and password,
you can easily crack there.
So every VPN have a vulnerability.
So if you, if you can able to execute the code in this, in this field or any, any username
and password field, so you can get into the machine, get into the organization easily.
So next we will go for a Sony call.
So here you can find the Sony call authentic, authentic data that we explore this.
So here you can find there is a 4, 4, W3, of open and does pointing towards the phone equality
info.
If, if there is a vulnerability or any, if you already have a credential, so we can,
log in into the organization, so we can get the credentials through the phishing and some
other, some other, attacks like if it's, if you have a, a credential stealer malware,
relatively, stealing the browser based credentials, username and passwords, so the attacker
will be easily getting the username and password, so he can able to, login into the machines
and he can do whatever he needs, right.
So, these are the simple examples of, of the attackers using the public facing applications
for their, for their initial access, okay.
So, let's stop off this video, I hope you have a clear understanding about external services,
not only the VPNs, there are a lot, lot of services will be available, maybe proxy or
any backup servers or any, any other Apache or any, a, a, emergency school servers, so
we can do a lot of things in that, okay.
So, they are using, basically, they are using publicly available external services, so
we, we'll be calling this kind of applications for Sony car as a publicly available, so
it is available to public, I can able to access, right.
I can able to access their portal, using login portal, so it's publicly accessible to anyone
including me, you and the hackers and the threat actors, anyone, so they will be using that
kind of that vulnerability or credentials, they will be logging into their organization,
okay.
Basically, they will be using this kind of EC, easy way to get into the organization without
any detection, okay.
Yep, we'll hop off this video and we will continue our discussion in the next video.
See you guys, bye bye.